<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>python3 on Bitperi(Periklis Gkolias)</title>
    <link>https://perigk.github.io/categories/python3/</link>
    <description>Recent content in python3 on Bitperi(Periklis Gkolias)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2019 22:04:50 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://perigk.github.io/categories/python3/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A Primer on Python Partial Functions</title>
      <link>https://perigk.github.io/posts/a-primer-on-partial-functions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2019 22:04:50 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://perigk.github.io/posts/a-primer-on-partial-functions/</guid>
      <description>Partial functions are one of the most &amp;ldquo;terrifying concepts&amp;rdquo; I hear people talking about. Personally, I think the idea is fairly easy to grasp. That is, I will try to explain in a few paragraphs with python and help you escape the math labyrinth of &amp;ldquo;official documentation&amp;rdquo;.
What is a partial function Partial functions are a computer science concept where we can derive a function with x parameters to a function with fewer parameters and constant values set for the more limited function.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generate cooking recipes that guarantee food poisoning, with LSTM based libraries</title>
      <link>https://perigk.github.io/posts/generate-cooking-recipes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 14:28:24 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://perigk.github.io/posts/generate-cooking-recipes/</guid>
      <description>Unless you are living in the Amazonian forest with no access to the Internet, there is literally no chance that you have not heard about the Deep Learning boom, of the last few years.
Training neural networks, that can make decisions, distinguish fake images or generate fake videos, in a relatively short time is becoming the norm.
It doesn&amp;rsquo;t all have to be scary though. Sometimes you can just have fun with all that power.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Django by example(Antonio Mele) - book review</title>
      <link>https://perigk.github.io/posts/django-example-book-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://perigk.github.io/posts/django-example-book-review/</guid>
      <description>Disclaimer: At the time of starting to write this article, the next version of the book under review, has not been published yet. If you want to read the newest version, you can find it here
Many people don&amp;rsquo;t have enough time to research for a book. I think such articles could help people, accelerate their (correct)decision.
That&amp;rsquo;s why I decided to write this article. This is a quick and dense review of Django by example by Antonio Mele</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Comprehensive Guide to Unit Testing with Python3</title>
      <link>https://perigk.github.io/posts/a-comprehensive-guide-to-unit-testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 17:05:18 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://perigk.github.io/posts/a-comprehensive-guide-to-unit-testing/</guid>
      <description>A comprehensive introduction to unit-testing and mocking with Python3 Unit testing is quickly becoming a must for all job adverts. There are a few people who don’t like Test Driven Development(TDD), but at least they agree on the value, automation testing(not only unit tests) add to the overall code quality and to the debugging process.
By the time of writing, according to dice.com, TDD is enjoying increased popularity year after year.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>