<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Books on Bitperi (Periklis Gkolias)</title>
    <link>https://perigk.github.io/tags/books/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Books on Bitperi (Periklis Gkolias)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 21:55:08 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://perigk.github.io/tags/books/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>I just finished Code complete cover to cover. Here are the most unexpected things I learned</title>
      <link>https://perigk.github.io/posts/code-complete-cover-to-cover/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 21:55:08 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://perigk.github.io/posts/code-complete-cover-to-cover/</guid>
      <description>I got code complete several years ago. Actually, it was a graduation gift.
I sometimes peaked into some of its chapters but never thought I was able to read it all at once. It was like a superhuman task for me.
Until this year, where I decided, in the game of no excuses, to play hard. One of the battles I chose to give was to finish the book.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Django by example(Antonio Mele) - book review</title>
      <link>https://perigk.github.io/posts/django-example-book-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://perigk.github.io/posts/django-example-book-review/</guid>
      <description>Disclaimer: At the time of starting to write this article, the next version of the book under review, has not been published yet. If you want to read the newest version, you can find it here
Many people don&amp;rsquo;t have enough time to research for a book. I think such articles could help people, accelerate their (correct)decision.
That&amp;rsquo;s why I decided to write this article. This is a quick and dense review of Django by example by Antonio Mele</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Must-read books for software engineers - the alternative list</title>
      <link>https://perigk.github.io/posts/hidden-gem-books-all-software-engineers-should-check/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://perigk.github.io/posts/hidden-gem-books-all-software-engineers-should-check/</guid>
      <description>There are tons of great books out there and a gazillion articles recommending them. The purpose of this article is not to recommend them again; I am pretty certain, that all such lists are very easy to be found with a few Google searches and no one needs me to tell him, that Code Complete is a must-read.
Thus, I&amp;rsquo;m going to list some books that are not very&amp;hellip;popular, but they are totally worth reading.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>