<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Productivity on Bitperi(Periklis Gkolias)</title>
    <link>https://perigk.github.io/categories/productivity/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Productivity on Bitperi(Periklis Gkolias)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2019 17:07:57 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://perigk.github.io/categories/productivity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>30 Tips for Software Engineering Careers, After 30 Years of Life</title>
      <link>https://perigk.github.io/posts/30-tips-for-software-engineering-careers-30-years-of-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2019 17:07:57 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://perigk.github.io/posts/30-tips-for-software-engineering-careers-30-years-of-life/</guid>
      <description>I turned 30, few days ago. An interesting decade, where I did and learned a lot of things came to an end. I tend to keep track of such &amp;ldquo;life lessons&amp;rdquo;, so I thought it would be a good idea to publicize the most related to our work life as software engineers.
Here we go:
1. Work really hard No one will grant you a promotion, salary increase or a better position for nothing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Survive a Noisy Office Environment</title>
      <link>https://perigk.github.io/posts/how-to-survive-noisy-office/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Oct 2018 23:03:29 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://perigk.github.io/posts/how-to-survive-noisy-office/</guid>
      <description>It is the most accepted fact after the great taste of ice-cream. Software engineers absolutely hate open plans or open offices.
They are noisy and tight, distracting, nerve breaking and the last thing they do is to help yu enter a state of flow. Unless you are lucky and your colleagues know the pain and behave accordingly.
Unfortunately, the open office, is an inevitable resource of our day to day work and it will be for the next few years, even though there are tons of voices against.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Definite Guide to Pick the Correct Music While Working</title>
      <link>https://perigk.github.io/posts/the-definite-guide-to-pick-the-correct-music-while-working/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2018 19:08:34 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://perigk.github.io/posts/the-definite-guide-to-pick-the-correct-music-while-working/</guid>
      <description>I only know few semi-god-concentration-giants who don&amp;rsquo;t work with headphones, while being productive at their company&amp;rsquo;s -usually noisy- office and I really admire them.
For the rest of us co-mortals, we need our headphones/earphones, to make it through. But have you ever thought, what should you listen to, at work? And I mean, in terms of best value regarding your current state.
Below are some hints, about how you should pick the sound that will entertain your ears.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>